我是奥利弗·奎恩
My name is Oliver Queen.
五年里  我被困在地狱一般的小岛上
After five years on a hellish island,
我回来只有一个目标
I have come home with only one goal--
拯救我的城市
To save my city.
但要达到目标  我不能像过去一样成为凶手
But to do so, I can't be the killer I once was.
为了纪念我的朋友  我只能伪装成另一个人
To honor my friend's memory, I must be someone else.
深切怀念托马斯·梅林
孝子
成为另一种存在
I must be something else.
《绿箭》前情回顾
Previously on "Arrow"...
艾沃杀了莎朵
Ivo killed Shado.
因为我选择了救你
Because I chose to save you.
杀害了莎朵的人还在逍遥法外
The man who killed Shado is still out there.
他不会逍遥很久的  因为我们要夺下货船
Not for long. Because we're going to take the freighter.
梅林才是西娅的亲生父亲
Merlyn is Thea's father.
但我认为你应该亲口告诉奥利弗
But I thought you deserved to tell Oliver yourself.
我是不会告诉我儿子任何事情的
I'm not going to tell my son anything.
西娅永远都不能知道梅林的事
Thea can never find out about Merlyn.
从现在开始  我们再无瓜葛
As of right now, we have no relationship.
我们之间再无关系
You and I are done.
亲爱的  你还好吗
Sweetheart, are you ok?
我们生活中出现的
Every single thing that's gone wrong
所有不愉快都是你的错
in our lives is your fault.
你给我滚
Now get out.
-对不起  -我让你滚
- I'm sorry. - I said, get out!
六秒后
In six seconds,
克罗企业
大厅里的保安会换班
lobby security will undergo a shift change.
到时候  你走到电梯里去
When that happens, make for the elevator bay.
收到
Copy.
记住我跟你说的
Now, remember what I told you--
时机就是一切
timing is everything.
保持每秒1.3秒的速度
Maintain a pace of 1.3 meters
六秒走到目标处
per second. Six seconds to target.
5, 4...
克罗企业
就是现在  先生们
Now is the time, gentlemen.
是指纹识别器  我破解不了
It's a fingerprint reader. I can't crack it.
我能
I can.
你们有5.3秒的时间走到东楼梯
You have 5.3 seconds to get down the east stairwell.
别走了
Stop!
我们在干什么
What the hell are we doing?
我们拿到了想要的东西
We got what we came for.
他说了等等
He said to wait.
在明处等着吗  别管了
Out in the open? Forget this.
别这样  别这样
Don't do it. Don't do it!
保安发现了我们
Security clocked us!
星城警局吗  你们得派点警官过来
SCPD? You've got to send some officers here.
上面  三楼  三楼
Up there, third floor. Third floor!
他们通知了星城警局
They've alerted the SCPD.
22秒内从东大厅的出口离开
Exit the east lobby in 22 seconds.
星城警局  放下武器
SCPD! Put your weapons down!
沃尔查克
Walczak!
DC52向搜查小队呼叫  市中心需要支援
Delta Charlie 52 to search, I need back-up, downtown!
离开这里  走开
Get out of here. Get out.
让开  让开
Move. Move.
一切权力归人民
Power to the people.
《绿箭》  第二季第十四集
狄格
Dig!
莎拉  对不起
Sara, I'm so sorry.
没关系  我没事
It's ok, I'm fine.
让我看看  让我看看
Let me see. Let me see.
她在流血  但是伤口不深
She's bleeding, but it's not deep.
真好  我不能再留疤了
Good, I can't take any more scars.
话说  你这是迫击炮留下的伤
Speaking of... mortar round?
是的  简易爆炸装置  在阿富汗的帕克迪卡省  眼力不错
Yeah, IED, the Paktika province in Afghanistan. Good eye.
伤口我很熟
I know my wounds.
手榴弹  在阿尔及尔
Grenade. Algiers.
我从没被手榴弹炸伤过
I've never been hit by a grenade.
你身上那么多伤疤  居然没被手榴弹炸伤过
All those scars, you've never been hit by a grenade?
箭伤  刀伤  刀伤
Arrow, knife, knife.
受过很多枪伤  没有手榴弹
A lot of bullets, no grenades.
我最近中弹了
I've got myself a new bullet.
九毫米  就在这
Nine millimeter, right there.
38毫米口径  我主要是剑伤  还有一处矛伤
.38. I'm mostly swords, and a spear.
我有一块伤疤
I have a scar.
在我嘴里
It's in my mouth.
16岁时我拔了智齿
I had my wisdom teeth removed when I was 16.
缝了三针  嵌得很紧
Three stitches. They were really badly impacted.
你还是很可爱
You're still cute.
我们该出发了
We should get going.
总不能在自己的欢迎派对上迟到
You don't want to be late for your own welcome home party.
你没必要给我开派对  奥利
You didn't have to throw me a party, Ollie.
莎拉  死里逃生  就得开派对
Sara, when you come back from the dead, you get a party.
这是奎恩家的传统
It's a Queen family tradition.
兰斯家的传统是永远记仇
I don't know how well that's going to work
好像咱家传统也没什么用啊
with the Lance family tradition of holding grudges forever.
她会想通的
She'll come around.
也许吧
Maybe.
也许我们该继续
And maybe we should keep what's going on
把我俩的事保密
between you and me between us.
为了劳蕾尔
For Laurel's sake.
我明白
I get that.
我连炼狱岛和南达尔巴特都挺过来了
I survived Lian Yu and Nanda Parbat,
一个鸡尾酒宴会还是应付得来的
I guess I can handle a cocktail party.
那可不一定
That wouldn't be so sure.
我们不可能做到
We're never going to make it.
艾沃有八名全副武装的保镖  随时待命
Ivo has eight guards on deck at all times, all armed.
一旦被看到  就是我们的死期
The second they see us, we're dead.
首先得处理艾沃的防御系统
Assuming we can deal with Ivo's defenses.
我们怎么靠近那艘船
How are we going to get close enough to board the ship?
我们可以造个木筏
Maybe we build a raft.
我们得花几个星期才能砍到足够的木材
It'll take us weeks to find the timber.
我们没那么多时间
We don't have weeks.
我在这座岛上待了264天
I've been on this island for 264 days.
我有的是时间
All I have is weeks.
闭嘴
Shut up.
你不用维护我  奥利
You don't have to stick up for me, Ollie.
什么  不是
What? No,
你们两个都别说话
both of you shut up.
听
Listen.
你们听到了吗
Do you hear that?
-在下面  -救命
- Hey, down here! - Help!
你让我们坐在监控摄像头前面
You left us sitting in front of the security camera.
保安完全可能杀了我们
Guards could have killed us.
你在听吗
Are you listening?
如果你们听我的
If you had simply waited
再静待五秒钟
for five more seconds, like you were told,
就没有人会死
No one would have died.
抱歉  我可不会把自己的生命
Sorry. I wasn't going to bet ten to twenty up in iron heights
赌在你那使用秒表的技能上
on your skills with a stopwatch.
"所有勇士中最强大的两个
"The strongest of all warriors
是时间与耐心"
are these two-- time and patience."
什么
What?
出自《战争与和平》
It's from "War and peace."
第1440页
1,440 pages.
书挺厚的  不过很值得阅读
It takes a while, but it's worth a read.
托尔斯泰知道耐心是力量的象征
Tolstoy knew that patience was the epitome of strength.
停下脚步需要勇气
It takes fortitude to stand still.
在不合时宜的时候行动
Just as it is a sign of weakness or cowardice
是弱者和懦夫的表现
to move when you should not!
听着
Look.
我们完成了工作  你欠我一个人情
We did the job. You owe me.
死后就一了百了
The dead are owed nothing.
进来吧  进来进来
Ah, come in. Come in, come in.
欢迎回家  莎拉
Welcome home, Sara.
你能来我真是太开心了  跟我来
I'm so happy you're here. Come on.
莎拉  这位是辛
Oh, Sara, this is Sin.
等等  你们两个认识吗
Wait, do you two know each other?
不  我们不认识
Uh, no. Uh, we don't.
没错  我只是很喜欢那些死而复生的人
Right. I just love when people come back from the dead, you know?
满足我的恋僵尸癖
Juices my zombie fetish.
我是罗伊
Um, Roy.
我是莎拉
Sara.
走吧
Come on.
抱歉
Sorry.
劳蕾尔  我是奥利
Laurel, it's Ollie.
奥利弗
来电
我希望你能来参加聚会
I hope you're coming to the party.
我听说你有点生莎拉的气
I heard that you maybe were a little mad at Sara,
而我...
And I...
她是你的妹妹  你只有这一个妹妹
She's your sister, and--and you only get one.
知道吗  再见
You know? Bye.
劳蕾尔不来
Laurel is not coming.
也许她需要时间
Well, maybe she just needs time.
是啊
Yeah.
我也需要时间
Yeah, I needed time, too.
当你回来的时候  我...
When you got back, I...
我对你非常严厉
Well, I was pretty harsh on you. Hey,
兰斯先生  你  你不需要
Mr. Lance, you--you don't have to--
我需要这么做
Oh, I do.
当你和莎拉一起上船出来的时候
When you and Sara went off on your dad's boat,
你还只是一个孩子  你们两个都是
you were just a kid, both of you were.
无论她能不能回来...
And whether she came back, or...
我太过分了
I was out of line.
你不是杀人犯  奥利弗
You're not a killer, Oliver.
-走吧  -走
- Yeah, - Come on, yeah.
我真为你高兴  黛娜
I'm so happy for you, Dinah.
奥利弗失踪的那五年
Those five years that Oliver was gone,
就像  我失去了我身体的一部分
was...like a piece of me was missing.
我明白你的感觉
I know just what you mean.
-抱歉  -没关系
- Oh, excuse me. - Of course.
没想到你会来
I didn't think you'd be here.
这是我家
This is my house.
如果你不想装作母子情深
And if you don't want to pretend to be mother and son,
那就别在我家办聚会
then don't throw parties in my home.
妈妈
Mom?
你和奥利之间没什么问题吧
Is everything ok with you and Ollie?
当然
Yes, of course.
你知道吗  我仍然难以相信
You know, I still can't quite believe it.
我从来不敢想象
I never really thought
莎拉会回到我们身边  昆汀
Sara would come back to us, Quentin.
是的  我知道
Yeah, I know.
抱歉
Excuse me.
我是兰斯
Lance.
我马上到
I'll be right there.
工作的事
It's work.
贫民区发生了杀人案件  我...
There's a homicide in the Glades, and I --
我得走了
I better go.
马上到
I'm on my way.
你怎么知道我要打来
How did you know I was calling?
因为兰斯警探也接到了电话
Because detective lance just got the same call.
怎么在每个案发现场都能见到你俩
What, you guys just show up to every crime scene now?
跟着你来的
I saw you leave.
鉴证科刚从一个叫艾迪·沃尔查克的人身上找到了这个
CSU just pulled this out of a skel I know named Eddie Walczak.
从没见过这样的刀
I've never seen a knife life this.
这不是刀  是个分针
It's not a knife, it's a minute hand,
应该是钟表上的
like from a clock.
几年前沃尔查克因非法闯入被我逮捕过
I popped Walczak f or B&E a few years back.
今早  他和一个同伙涉嫌一起抢劫杀人案
This morning, he and an accomplice were involved in a robbery homicide.
他们偷了什么
What'd they steal?
什么高科技的玩意
Some high-tech gizmo.
科尔德的人管它叫  万能钥匙
Kord rep called it a, um, skeleton key.
怎么  你知道那是什么吗
What? You know what it is?
那是军方用于破解地方智能目标密码
It was intended as a military tool to aid in code breaking
而发明的一个解码器
on foreign intelligence targets.
奎恩联合企业的费利西蒂·斯莫克
Felicity Smoak works at queen consolidated
说企业本来也在研制类似的东西
and she said they were working on something similar...
但奥利弗·奎恩停止了计划
but Oliver Queen shut it down once he realized
因为意识到了它的作用
what it could be used for.
什么作用
What?
稍加改进  它就可以打开金库
It could be modified to open a bank vault,
任何金库
any bank vault.
但是沃尔查克可没那么高智商
Ok, listen -- Walczak's small-time on a good day.
我怀疑他甚至都不会用这玩意
I mean, I doubt he'd even know how to use this thing,
更不要说能闯进科尔德把它偷出来了
let alone break into a place like Kord and steal it on his own.
沃尔查克只是个傀儡
Walczak was just the muscle.
我们要找的是幕后主使
We need to find the brain.
双脚间距拉开
Plant your feet.
这样才站得稳
Strong foundation.
这样出拳才更有力
Equals stronger punch.
不错
Nice.
你要是为了防身  我建议你练咏春
If this is for self defense, I'd recommend wing chun.
它的原理是借力打力
It uses your opponent's strength against him.
很适合身材娇小的人群
So it's ideal for smaller people...
比如我们
like us.
看来你一定照顾得好自己咯
You seem like you can take care of yourself just fine.
你没事吧
Are you ok?
万能钥匙找得怎么样了
Where are we with the skeleton key?
而且你  怎么穿成这样
And what... are you wearing?
我只是想...
I just thought I'd...
正在将沃尔查克的已知同伙
I'm cross referencing Walczak's known associates
和国家安全局解密专家的监视名单做对比
with decryption experts on the NSA watch list,
但是需要时间
but it's taking some time,
问题在于没时间了
which we don't have.
钥匙不仅是个解密器
Ok, the key is not just a code breaker.
落进坏人手里  它完全就是武器
in the wrong hands, it's a weapon.
那个杀掉沃尔查克的人
whoever killed Walczak,
奇怪到用钟表零件杀人的人
in addition to finding creepy uses for clock parts,
很会掩藏踪迹
is very good at covering his tracks.
我们很幸运  搜查追踪
Lucky for us, uncovering tracks
正是你的强项
is what you're very good at.
是啊
Right.
果然坏了
Of course.
他快死了
He's barely alive.
我们还有医疗用品吗
Do you have medical supplies at the fuselage?
应该  不多了
We have -- we have some.
快去拿  我应付得了
Just go. I'll be fine.
我开始后悔给你一把钥匙了
I'm really starting to regret giving you a key.
抱歉我没去参加派对
I'm sorry I bailed on the party.
我猜到了
Ah, I figured you wouldn't make an appearance.
终于有人理解我了
Finally, someone understands.
我还没厉害到能理解你
Well, I, uh, I wouldn't go that far.
但是我理解  莎拉没告诉我们她还活着
But I understand how Sara keeping it a secret
确实很伤人
that she was still alive could hurt.
因为我也伤心
'Cause it hurt me, too.
怎么听起来你要说"但是"了
I sense a "But" Coming in my future.
没错  但是我希望你能原谅此事
But, yes, but I need you to move past it.
劳蕾尔
Laurel.
来个家庭聚餐吧
A family dinner.
也是个和解的机会嘛
It's a chance to reconcile.
我不想和莎拉和解
I don't want to reconcile with Sara.
我没说是为了让你俩和解
I'm not talking about you and Sara.
我是说想让...
I'm talking about...
我和你妈和解
me and your mom.
你什么意思
What do you mean?
我不知道该怎么说
I don't know to describe it.
就是感觉我们俩不对劲
It was like there was, um...signals,
直觉吧
and feelings.
我也不知道怎么回事
And I'm not exactly sure what's going on,
但我想要是我们一家人在一起
but I figured if we were all together as a family,
也许能让她想起我们曾经那么幸福
maybe it would remind her of how happy we were.
懂吗
You know?
我也不知道  也许吧...
I mean, I don't know, maybe it...
我是不是很傻
is it stupid?
不会  这...
No, it...
我是警员DC52  请讲
Go for Delta-Charlie 52.
发生抢劫杀人案
415 in progress.
地点是维德米银行  副队要求全小队过去
Widmeer bank. Lieutenant requesting all units.
警员DC52收到
Delta-Charlie 52 responding.
我得走了
I got to go.
今天晚上
Tonight.
八点半
8:30.
-喊大家过来  -怎么了
- Tell everyone to be here. - What?
你家太小了
Well, your place is too small,
我无意冒犯  只是你家挺乱的  所以
and, no offense, it's kind of a mess, so...
- 宝贝  -好啦
- Oh, sweetheart. - OK.
我爱你  甜心
I love you, sweetheart.
-设备准备好了  -3.2秒
- Device is hot. - 3.2 seconds.
九十秒内全力抢钱去吧
Extract as much money as you can in 90 seconds.
停  出去
Stop! Get out of there!
我们还有二十秒的时间
We've still got 20 seconds.
没有时间了
No, you don't.
撤
Come on!
他们已经逃了
They're already gone!
我估计知道在哪
I think I have an idea where.
万能钥匙是通过正交频分的无线信号起作用的
The Skeleton Key operates on an OFDM wireless signal.
我收到了银行边上的
I'm picking up a transmission signal
一条小巷发出的传输信号
in the alley next to the bank.
但是你们不会去那的
But you won't be heading there.
什么声音
What was that?
他黑进了我们的传输信号
He's hacked our transmission.
我的同伴可能会撤到巷子
My associates may be headed to the alley,
但从新月环来的910路公交
but the 910 bus from Crescent Circle
十字路口畅通
就要和星光快递的火车相撞了
is about to collide with the Starlight Freight Express.
十字路口警报
我的天  他说中了
Oh, my god, he's right,
910路公交正开在艾摩斯特街的路上
the 910's headed for the track at Amherst.
要我看  你总不能同时出现在两个地方
By my calculations, you can't be in two places at once.
他不知道我们有两个人
He doesn't know there's two of us.
910路  新月环
快  快
Come on! Come on!
访问拒绝
他进入了交通部的网络
He's in the transit department network!
十字路口警报
他黑进了信号系统
He's--he's hacked the signaling system.
我没法放置十字路口的路障
I--I can't get the crossing barriers down!
公交车上有对讲机
Those buses have radios.
你能黑进去  告诉司机停车吗
Can you break in, wave them off?
不能  他拦住我了
No, he's keeping me out.
时钟国王敲了两次钟
媒体没取昵称之前  这事都毫无真实感
I guess it's not real until the media comes up with a nickname.
我开酒吧怎么能没有调酒师呢
How can I run a bar without any bartenders?
说到这个  你怎么能
For that matter, how can you quit
一声不吭就跑人了呢
without giving me notice?
不  开门前一小时才告知我
No, one hour before opening
就不叫做提前告知  曼蒂
is not notice, Mandy.
我能和你谈谈吗
Can I talk to you for a second?
我去金发妞的房间里待一会
I'm going to go use the little blonde's room.
都还好吗
Everything ok?
你说呢
You tell me.
除了派对
Other than the party,
我还没见过你有在家待过一整周
I haven't seen you at home all week.
我可是个大忙人
I've been busy.
总裁的事情多得让我都没时间做别的了
Being a CEO doesn't leave me a lot of free time.
是吗  在我看来你比较像是在躲着妈妈
Yeah, looks to me a whole lot like you're avoiding mom.
我没在躲她
I'm not avoiding mom.
你该庆幸自己的生活并不是充斥着谎言
You're lucky your life does not revolve around lying.
西娅
Thea.
一切都很好
Everything's fine.
秘密是最先开始导致
You know, it's secrets
家庭四分五裂的原因  奥利
that pushed this family apart in the first place, Ollie.
闪电妞  闪电妞  我说真的
Speedy, Speedy. Really.
一切都好
Everything's fine.
现在什么情况
What do we know?
他黑进了我们的无线信号
He hacked into our frequency,
不知道他怎么获得了远程访问权限
somehow gained remote access,
我升级了防火墙
but I upgraded our firewall.
现在除非他有火箭炮
Now he won't be able to
否则他是不可能黑进我们的通信了
talk into our comms even if he had a bazooka.
我是说  是电脑通信这方面的火箭炮
You know... computer science-wise.
很好
Good.
这东西可能会帮我们抓到他
I think I have something that might help us track him down.
可以给我拿去实验室做测试
I can run that to the lab.
我在货船上曾花了一年时间研究血液基因变异
I spent a year on the freighter studying genetic blood anomalies.
显微镜实验方面我也算是行家了
I kind of know my way around a microscope.
细胞被严重破坏
There's some significant cell damage
血小板数量极低
and the platelet count is extremely low.
费利西蒂  我能借用下你的电脑吗
Felicity, can I use your computer?
麦克格瑞格综合症  这是一种遗传缺失
Macgregor's syndrome. It's a genetic defect
会在肺部积水
that creates fluid build-up in the lungs,
导致缺氧和多器官衰竭
which leads to oxygen deprivation and multi system organ failure.
到晚期了
It's terminal.
这个综合症也许能帮我们确认他的身份
But the syndrome may give us a way to ID him.
患麦克格瑞格综合症的人极少
People with macgregor's are extremely rare,
患有此综合症
and people with macgregor's and
有计算机学位的人更少见
a degree in computer science are even more rare.
威廉·塔克曼  前编码工程师
William Tockman. Former encryption engineer at,
好戏来了  在科尔德实业工作
wait for it-- Kord Enterprises.
这么做的意义在哪里
What's the point?
他在把钱花光前就死了
He'll be dead before he can spend all the money.
他不是为了自己而去偷钱的
He's not stealing the money for himself.
他是为了他的家人  特别是他的姐姐
He's using it for his family. His sister, specifically.
她有囊胞性纤维症  需要肺移植
She's got cystic fibrosis and needs a lung transplant.
把地址给我  谢谢
Give me an address, please.
纳尔逊路52号
52 Nelson Way.
这区域看起来可不太像是住宅区
This area doesn't look very residential.
就是这儿了
There.
那是塔克曼的车
That's Tockman's ride.
塔克曼不在这儿  只留下了些装置
Tockman's not here. Just some device.
我在查了  卡车里的那个装置正在传输
I'm on it. Whatever's in the truck
和塔克曼在银行用的相同的正交频分复用信号
is transmitting the same OFDM signal Tockman used at the bank.
-你能追踪吗  -已经开始了
- Can you trace it? - As we speak.
信号追踪到了...我们的网络
It's leading... back to our network.
塔克曼盗用了我的入侵线路  这是个陷阱
Tockman's piggybacking off my hack. It's a trap.
他想要入侵我们的网络
He--he's trying to break into our network.
我不是想入侵
I'm not trying.
我就在入侵
I am.
你在哪儿
Where are you?
你在家吗
Are you home?
你安全吗
Are you safe?
你感到安全的一个地方
Somewhere you think you're safe...
在一个没有窗户来让人爬进的地方吗
Somewhere without windows for anyone to creep through?
有可能是地下
Underground, perhaps?
你觉得没人能找到你吗
You think no one can get to you?
你觉得藏在安全避风港里
You think no one can touch you
就没人会碰到你吗
in the safety of your hidey hole?
费利西蒂
Felicity...
但是我可以
But I can.
有多槽糕
How bad?
塔克曼用万能钥匙
Tockman used the skeleton key
侵入了我们的防火墙
to penetrate our firewall.
并且重新编码了我们的安全系统
And recode our security.
基本上他让我们的系统去自毁
Basically, he told our system to commit suicide.
结果还成功了
And it did.
漫画中的超级大恶人
精彩  同步信号之王
Bravo, clock king.
莎拉在塔克曼的人可以卷钱而逃之前
Sara stopped Tockman's men before they could
制止了他们
get away with the cash.
所以塔克曼一定会再干一票
So Tockman is going to be looking for another score.
或许我们应该给他创造机会
Maybe we should give him one.
你能不能打给沃尔特让他清算出
Would you call Walter and have him liquidate
奎恩集团股票里的五十万股
500,000 shares of QC stock?
把现金放进我在星城国民银行的保险库中
Put it in cash in my vault at Starling National,
让他今晚就做
and ask him to do it tonight.
如果塔克曼想再干一票的话
If Tockman wants to make another score...
谁还能比忽然有大把现金的
Who better to rob than a suddenly
奥利弗·奎恩更值得去抢呢
cash flush Oliver Queen?
那如果他不上当怎么办
And what if he doesn't take the bait?
有道理  八十万股好了
That's a good point. Make it 800,000 shares.
好的  我能做些什么呢
Ok. What can I do?
赴约去吃晚餐
Go to your dinner.
你的家人或许在等着你呢
Your family's probably waiting for you.
是啊
Right.
在劳蕾尔家吃晚餐
Dinner at Laurel's.
这件事更重要
This is more important.
你在这里无能无力  莎拉
You can't do anything here, Sara.
你的家人也很重要
Your family's important, too.
是的
Yeah.
你应该赴约
You should go.
你能跟我一块去吗
Will you go with me?
什么
What?
我知道我想让一家人团聚很久了
I know I've wanted us all to get together for a while now.
只是现在真到了这个地步  我很紧张
It's just, now that it's actually here, I'm nervous.
上一次我见到劳蕾尔的时候  并不顺利
I mean, last time I saw Laurel, it...didn't go very well,
而且
And...
如果有人作伴的话会很有帮助
It'd be helpful to not have to go alone.
我或许应该待在这里
I should probably stay here.
你在这儿又能帮什么忙呢
What is it exactly you think you can do here to help?
如果需要我们就打电话
Call if you need us.
好的
Yep.
这不是你的错  费利西蒂
You know, it's not your fault, Felicity.
是吗  你们中还有谁能
Really? Which one of the rest of you
提供安全维护
put up the security safeguards?
也许如果是莎拉的话
Maybe if it been Sara,
我们现在就不会一团糟了
we wouldn't be in this mess.
我知道我们没有谈过这个
Now, I know we haven't talked about this,
但是他们俩在一起你一定很难受吧
but it must be difficult for you seeing them together.
这不是他们俩在一起的问题
This isn't about them being together.
这是我自己的问题  莎拉可以分析血液
This is about me. Ok, Sara can analyze blood.
拳打脚踢  她无所不能
She can kick ass. She can do anything.
唯一一件我应该做好的事情
And the one thing I'm supposed to be good at,
我也悲剧地搞砸了
I'm failing at miserably.
现在既然有了她  还需要我干什么呢
And why do you even need me now that you have her?
因为你是无可取代的  费利西蒂
Because you're irreplaceable, Felicity.
我还有很多事要做
I have a lot of work to do.
劳蕾尔  莎拉来了
Laurel, Sara's here.
你好  妈妈
Hey, mom.
你好
Hi.
奥利弗  谢谢
Oliver. Well, thank you,
花很漂亮
These are lovely.
谢谢
Thank you.
我怎么不记得你也姓兰斯呢
I don't remember your last name being Lance.
其实我也不想毁了你们的家庭聚餐
Well, yeah, I certainly didn't want to crash your family dinner,
但是我刚好在路上遇到莎拉
But then...sara and I ran into each other,
她邀请我来
and she mentioned it.
我告诉他爸爸会做最拿手的烩鸡块
And I told him how dad was making his famous chicken cacciatore.
实际上  抱歉
Actually--excuse me!
我们要  奥利弗
We're, uh, we're--oliver.
你好  兰斯先生
Hey, Mr. Lance.
是的  晚饭只能吃匹萨了  真是抱歉
Yeah. Um, we're having pizza. I'm sorry.
我把晚饭弄砸了
I had a little incident in the kitchen.
如果六年都没过碰烤箱
I guess that's what happens when you haven't
搞砸也就不奇怪了
used an oven in six years.
来块儿匹萨吧
Want to grab a slice?
我正要把鸡肉块垒成塔状
Yeah, when I was pitching a tower of caccitore--
没错  是烩鸡块塔
a cacciatore tower, yeah.
您还在教书吗  兰斯夫人
Are you still teaching, Mrs. Lance?
是的  在中央城市大学
Yes, I am. Greek and medieval history
教希腊历史和中世纪历史
at Central City University.
你也该考虑递交辞职信了吧
You could probably give them notice.
我为什么要那么做
Why would I do that?
我的意思是  你要搬回星城了  对吗
Well, I mean, you're going to come back to Starling, right?
不
No.
我没打算搬回星城  昆汀
I'm not moving back to Starling, Quentin.
莎拉回来了
Well, Sara's back.
我在那有新的生活
I have a new life in Central city
很棒的工作
and I have a wonderful job.
工作在哪儿都有啊
Well, there's jobs here.
不只是工作
More than a job.
我认识了  一个人
Um...I have... someone.
这样  那恭喜你了
Oh... congratulations.
其实这挺好的  妈妈
You know, it's great, mom.
你应该过得快乐些
You deserve to be happy.
大家都应该过得快乐些
Everybody does.
告诉我这不是真的
You've got to be kidding me.
什么
What?
你才回来多久  一个礼拜
You've been back like, what, a week?
你们甚至都不否认一下  是吗
And you're not even denying it.
没有那么简单
It's...it's complicated.
当然了  有你怎么可能简单
Of course it is. It's you.
劳蕾尔  拜托了
Laurel, please.
爸爸  你的处境也好不到哪去
Dad, you are no better than they are.
你真的以为
I mean, what did you think,
妈妈会心甘情愿等你的鸡块
mom was just going to sit around and wait for you for six years
六年时间吗
to bake her chicken?
劳蕾尔  别说了
Ok, Laurel, enough!
还是期待她会回心转意
And sweep her back off her feet?
你说够了没有
Enough, ok?
没错  你知道吗  我是够了
Yeah, you know what, it is enough!
吃完了就滚出这里
Invite yourselves out when you're done.
我的钱包
My wallet.
好的
Ok.
这是我女儿
She's my daughter.
她12岁
She's 12.
我需要和她讲话
I need to talk to her.
你的对讲机坏掉了
Your radio's broken.
她妈妈在她婴儿时就死了
Her mother died just after she got out of diapers.
死于癌症
Cancer.
除了我
And without me...
连一个照顾她的人都没有了
she's not going to have anybody to look after her.
所以
So...
我知道我并不认识你
I know I don't know you.
你也不认识我
And I know you don't know me.
但是
But...
求求你一定要确保我女儿平安
please make sure my daughter's OK.
求求你
Please.
你简直令人难以置信
You are unbelievable!
是你告诉我  我需要修复
You lecture me on how I need to repair my relationship with Sara
我和莎拉之间被你破坏的关系
when you're the one who messed it up in the first place.
就因为你俩有一腿
By screwing her!
而现在你要重蹈覆辙
And now you're doing it again.
你说得对  是我的错
You're right. This is all my fault.
没错  是你的错
Yeah. Yeah, yes, it is.
你丢了工作  开始吸毒酗酒
And is you losing your job, doing drugs and being a drunk,
也是我的错吗
is that my fault?
是你家人的错吗
Is that your family's fault,
还是要归咎于汤米的死呢
or are you going to blame Tommy for dying?
去你的  奥利弗
Screw you, Oliver.
自始至终我都是支持你的
I used stood by you through everything--
无论是你酒驾被罚  丢掉工作
the DUI, losing your job,
还是你努力想让我母亲被判死刑时  劳蕾尔
and Laurel, I was concerned about your well-being
我一直都在为你的身心考虑
when you were trying to get my mother the death penalty!
是啊  你可真是个正直的人啊
Yeah, you've been a real stand-up kind of guy.
劳蕾尔  你以为只有你自己
Laurel, do you think you're the only one
很不好过吗
that is having a hard time?!
你以为只有你一个人有家庭问题吗
Do you think you're the only one with family issues?
你完全...你完全不知道
You have-- you have no idea
我家里现在发生了什么事
what is going on with my family right now.
但我还站在这里
But I am still standing here.
而你还在指责除你以外的所有人
And you are still blaming everybody but yourself.
你说够了吗
Are you done?
是的
Yeah.
是的  我够了
Yeah, I'm done.
我受指责受够了
I'm done taking the blame.
也关心够了
And I'm done caring.
你去喝一杯吧
Why don't you go have a drink?
喝醉点  去吧
Get wasted, go...
去威登吧
Go to Verdant.
我买单
I'll pay for it.
我爱你爱了半生
I have loved you for half my life.
但我追够你了
But I'm done running after you.
你看见费利西蒂了吗
Have you seen Felicity?
没有  等等  怎么了
No. Wait, why?
我去大贝利汉堡店买了些外卖
I went to Big Belly to get some take-out.
我回来的时候  她就不在了
When I came back, she was gone.
我好几个小时没看见她了
I haven't seen her for hours.
塔克曼上钩了  就是你让沃尔特存的那笔钱
Tockman took the bait. The money you had Walter deposit.
我在星城国民银行读取他的信号
I'm reading his signal at Starling National.
等等  你怎么知道的
Wait...how do you know that?
-因为我就在这里  -什么
- Because I'm here. - What?!
你在这儿干什么
What are you doing here?
我在追踪塔克曼
I'm tracking Tockman.
他弄坏了我们的电脑  所以我用银行的电脑
He fried our computers, so I'm using the bank's
追踪万能钥匙的信号
to trace the skeleton key's signature.
那夹克是怎么回事
And the jacket?
我很冷
I was cold.
狄格尔  把她弄出去
Diggle, get her out of here.
塔克曼弄坏了银行的安保系统
Tockman disabled the bank's security system.
我重新弄好了
I re-abled it.
他们在阻截我们的出路
They're blocking our way out.
我去处理他们
I'll deal with them.
塔克曼的信号很强
Tockman's signal's strong.
他就在这儿  很近
He's here, he's close.
找到他  费利西蒂
Find him, Felicity.
不需要
No need.
我告诉你们我的准确位置
I'll tell you exactly where I am.
我无处不在
I'm everywhere.
现在  我正在关注地下
At the moment, I'm particularly focused on the sub-level.
确切的说  是燃气管道
The gas mains, specifically.
天啊  他关闭了煤气排放
Oh, my god. He shut down the gas main release.
这为什么不好
And why is that bad?
积聚多了会引起爆炸
The build-up could cause an explosion.
会的  会炸毁周围三个街区
It will. It'll blow up three square blocks.
不  不会的
No, it won't.
等等  塔克曼太过于炫耀了
Wait. Tockman overplayed his hand.
煤气管道在全市联网中  那是我的地盘
The gas main's in the city's network, that's where I live.
我该理解你的话吗
Am I supposed to understand that?
他想要炸飞我们
Ohh. In trying to blow us up,
这也给了我一个扳倒他的机会
he gave me a way to track him down.
这我理解
That I understood.
发生了什么
What's happening?
小心
Look out!
你都不知道我为什么要这么做
You don't even know why I'm doing this.
钱不是给我的
The money's not for me!
我做这一切都是为了她
I'm doing this all for her!
那也不对
Doesn't make it right.
光阴似箭[拉丁文]
Tempus fugit.
光阴似箭
Time flies.
那是什么
What the hell was that?
他的手机
His cell phone.
我给他安装了
I uploaded the same virus
他装在我铸造厂里装备上同样的病毒
he used on my gear in the foundry.
我没杀死他吧
I didn't just kill him, did I?
只是把他弄昏了
Just knocked him out.
-我们做到了  -是你做到了
- We did it. - You did it.
你确定不想去医院
Are you sure you don't want to go to the hospital?
你们就从不去医院
You guys never go to the hospital.
另外  狄格给了我几片那种阿司匹林
Besides, Dig gave me some of those aspirins.
你在旋转吗
Are you spinning?
止疼药
-阿司匹林  -盐酸羟考酮
- Aspirin? - Oxycodone.
如果不是你那么勇敢
I wouldn't be here
我现在就不在这里了  谢谢
if you hadn't been so brave. Thank you.
没事
It was nothing.
我一直想说我为某人挡了一颗子弹
I've always wanted to say I've taken a bullet for someone,
现在我可以说了
and now I can.
所以说真的  我该感谢你
So really I should be thanking you.
都好了
All done.
不严重  但你依旧会留疤
Not bad, but you're still going to have a scar.
我自己的伤疤
My own scar.
好啊
Yay.
你还好吗
You all right?
狄格尔说你可能感觉有一点...
Diggle had mentioned that maybe you were feeling...
被忽视了
a little left out.
什么  没有
What? No.
我只是...
I was just...
习惯了做你的女人
used to being your girl.
不是你的那种女人
I mean, not your girl-girl.
是你的女人
Your girl.
我知道这是同一个词
I know it sounds like the same word,
但对我来说含义不同
but it means something different in my head.
你永远都是我的女人  费利西蒂
You will always be my girl, Felicity.
我能再吃一片阿司匹林吗
Can I have another one of those aspirins?
威登酒吧
尝尝这个
Try this.
不错吧
Good, huh?
真的很不错
It's really good.
你怎么在这里调酒呢
And what are you doing back here mixing drinks?
西娅雇了我
Thea hired me.
我是新的调酒师了
I am the new bartender.
上大学的时候我做过调酒师  而且
I bartended in college, and, uh, well,
对于简历亮点是国际杀手的人来说
it's kind of hard to get a job
找工作好像有点困难
when international assassin is the highlight of you resume.
你会做得很好的
You're going to do great.
来自西娅的短信: 家里出事了
我得回趟家
I have to go home.
有什么事吗
Is everything ok?
希望没有
I hope so.
你可以放心地走
You can go.
我来这不是要杀她的
I'm not here to kill her or anything.
我还记得你以前在一家
I remember you used to bartend
很破的酒吧里做调酒师
at that skeevy bar with the...
那里地上到处都是花生皮
peanut shells all over the floor.
奥博丽薇酒吧
Oblivion.
没错
Right.
我不是来这喝酒的
I'm not here for a drink or anything.
那你来这干什么
Then why are you here?
因为我觉得
Because I realized that...
我好像也上了那艘船
that I went on that boat with you, too.
而且
And...
这些年来
I've been slowly
我也慢慢地沉了下去
drowning for all of these years.
经历过各种心碎
And after every heartbreak or
挫折  失败之后
set-back or loss...
我沉到了黑暗的海底
I sank deeper into the dark water.
但当我见到你时
And so when I saw you,
你是那么美丽
so beautiful,
那么充满活力
and so alive,
我才意识到这些我都没有
I realized that I'm not those things.
不再有了
Not anymore.
所以  求你了
So please...
求你不要恨我  莎拉
please don't hate me, Sara.
求你了
Please.
天啊  我想死你了
God. I missed you.
我以为什么事都不能让你掉眼泪呢
Didn't think anything could make you cry.
看来我没有你想的那么坚强
Guess I'm not as tough as you thought.
那
So...
你这毁了的烟熏妆是怎么回事
why the running mascara?
我刚才
I had--
我刚才跟我姐姐见面了
I just had a moment with my sister.
是一次很好的见面
It was a good one.
那就好
That's good.
虽然劳蕾尔是我的姐姐
Hey, Laurel's my big sister.
但我也愿意有一个你这样的妹妹
I still have room for a little one.
真好
Good.
我不知道如果没有你我会怎样
I don't know what I'd do without you.
你不用知道的
Well, you won't have to find out.
我要去找罗伊了
I'm going to go find Roy.
我们在比赛时
2008年5月10日
找到了
Got it.
太晚了
It's too late.
他已经死了
He's gone.
我们都会死在这里
We're all going to die here.
像他一样
Just like him.
不  不会的
No, we're not.
我想我找到了上货船的办法
I think I found our way on to the freighter.
降落伞
Parachute.
西娅
Thea!
奥利弗  怎么了
Oliver. What's wrong?
一切都好吗
Is everything all right?
西娅给我发短信说家里出事了
Thea texted me there was an emergency at the house.
没出事  我正在开会
No emergency. I'm in the middle of a meeting
西娅都没在家里
and Thea's not even here.
那她为什么
Well, then why would she...
-我真不敢相信她竟然这么做了  -做什么
- I can't believe she would do this. - Do what?
她这是强迫我们俩坐下来谈谈
She's trying to force us to talk
因为她感觉到了我们之间紧张的气氛
because she's sensing the tension between us.
你跟她说了什么
And what did you tell her?
什么也没说
Nothing.
那是为了保护她
To protect her.
不是为了你
Not you.
奎恩夫人  一切都好吗
Mrs. Queen. Is everything ok?
是的  谢谢你关心
Yes, thank you.
我儿子来看我了
Uh, my son just dropped by.
奥利弗  来见见斯莱德·威尔逊
Oliver, I'd like you to meet Slade Wilson.
很高兴见到你
It's a pleasure to meet you...
奎恩先生
Mr. Queen.